<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cncf on Kubermates</title><link>https://kubermates.org/tags/cncf/</link><description>Recent content in Cncf on Kubermates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kubermates.org/tags/cncf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Native Talks: Tales of SREs and Kubernetes Security</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cloud-native-talks-tales-of-sres-and-kubernetes-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cloud-native-talks-tales-of-sres-and-kubernetes-security/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rafael Ordoñez, Ionik Tech (Málaga): Walking Through Our SRE Journey – A Storytelling Approach (English)Saed Farah, Goog&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Timisoara - Autumn Edition 2025</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cloud-native-timisoara-autumn-edition-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cloud-native-timisoara-autumn-edition-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss this opportunity to expand your knowledge and network with like-minded professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Taipei</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-ctencf-birthday-bash-taipei/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-ctencf-birthday-bash-taipei/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;（本活動於 2025/08/21 12:00 PM (UTC+8) 開放 RSVP，需收 50 元場地費，歡迎大家來一同參與！）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CNCF 10 週年紀念活動！&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CNCF On-Demand: One API to Rule Them All - Building a Unified Platform with Kubernetes Aggregation</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cncf-on-demand-one-api-to-rule-them-all-building-a-unified-platform-with-kuberne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-cncf-on-demand-one-api-to-rule-them-all-building-a-unified-platform-with-kuberne/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you build a unified product from open-source tools? A Cozystack maintainer shares the journey of integrating Helm, Operators, and Kubernetes’ Aggregation Layer to create a general-purpose API—without etcd. Learn how they built a dynamic API server, universal GUI for operators, and real-time b&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Barcelona</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-ctencf-birthday-bash-barcelona/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-04-ctencf-birthday-bash-barcelona/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;#cTENcf #celebrateCNCF, which will celebrate 10 years of the CNCF&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paving a Golden Path: Cloud-Native Lessons on Developer Experience with Thomas Schuetz</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-03-paving-a-golden-path-cloud-native-lessons-on-developer-experience-with-thomas-sc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-03-paving-a-golden-path-cloud-native-lessons-on-developer-experience-with-thomas-sc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an enlightening session titled &amp;ldquo;Paving a Golden Path: What Going Cloud-Native Taught us About Developer Expe&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fall Kickoff at UW-Madison</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-fall-kickoff-at-uw-madison/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-fall-kickoff-at-uw-madison/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Big congrats to UW–Madison for being named to LinkedIn’s inaugural Top Colleges list for long-term career success—perfec&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cartografos Community Meeting</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-cartografos-community-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-cartografos-community-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bi-weekly community meeting for the Cartografos Working Group.
The Cartografos working group aims to provide tools to help adopters and end-users to navigate the CNCF landscape and the wider cloud native ecosystem.
Please come along - we invite all attendees.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Merge Forward Monthly Meeting</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-merge-forward-monthly-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-merge-forward-monthly-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the monthly Merge Forward meeting, where representatives from all Merge Forward diversity groups get together. E&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chaos Mesh Development Meeting</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-chaos-mesh-development-meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-02-chaos-mesh-development-meeting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a biweekly meeting to discuss anything related to the project development.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unlocking Platform Engineering for Organizational Success and The Journey to the Beginning of the Edge with Talos Kubernetes</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-01-unlocking-platform-engineering-for-organizational-success-and-the-journey-to-the/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-09-01-unlocking-platform-engineering-for-organizational-success-and-the-journey-to-the/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an exciting evening where we dive into two transformative topics:First, discover the world of Team Topologie&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf party - USAC - 10 años de CNCF</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-party-usac-10-a-os-de-cncf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-party-usac-10-a-os-de-cncf/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Celebrate 10 years of CNCF!, Nuestra comunidad esta celebrando los 10 años de CNCF, 10 años, 200 proyectos y más de 275000 contribuidores, únete a nosotros en la USAC para celebrar juntos.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CKA Bootcamp by CNCG Gandhinagar - Week 1</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-cka-bootcamp-by-cncg-gandhinagar-week-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-cka-bootcamp-by-cncg-gandhinagar-week-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 CKA Bootcamp – Master Kubernetes with Hands-On LearningGet ready to take your Kubernetes skills to the next level!Foll&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash São Paulo</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-s-o-paulo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-s-o-paulo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Bem-vindos ao chapter Cloud Native São Paulo! 🇧🇷
Somos um grupo oficial da CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation) que tem como propósito contribuir para a comunidade Cloud Native e Open Source.
Estimulamos a conexão entre entusiastas da tecnologia através de encontros virtuais e presenciais, com w&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Dhaka</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-dhaka/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-dhaka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Celebrating the 10th year of CNCF Communities and the CNCF LandscapeRegister using the form: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/UjHUpuPvF"&gt;https://forms.gle/UjHUpuPvF&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Mauritius August Meetup</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-cloud-native-mauritius-august-meetup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 06:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-cloud-native-mauritius-august-meetup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following DevCon, Cloud Native meetups are back. Join us on the 30th of August to learn about Cloud Native technologies &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Gurugram</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-gurugram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-30-ctencf-birthday-bash-gurugram/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A #cTENcf regional event Exploring the Future of Cloud This edition is extra special — we’re celebrating 10 Years of CN&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deep Dive into Kubernetes Networking</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-29-deep-dive-into-kubernetes-networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-29-deep-dive-into-kubernetes-networking/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes networking is a core component of every cluster, yet it remains one of the most misunderstood areas. In this &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Istio- it Is! &amp; Optimizing DNS Queries</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-istio-it-is-optimizing-dns-queries/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-istio-it-is-optimizing-dns-queries/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone is invited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in for a treat with two amazing talks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vishwa Gandhi from Oracle on &amp;ldquo;Istio- it Is!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a last-minute change, and the second talk of the evening will now be our friend Goutam Tadi, Astronomer.io. Infra Engineering, Staff Software Engineer on &amp;ldquo;Optimizing DNS queries&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Birmingham</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-ctencf-birthday-bash-birmingham/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-ctencf-birthday-bash-birmingham/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an exciting meetup to celebrate 10 years of the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) and its impact on t&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>#cTENcf Birthday Bash Dublin</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-ctencf-birthday-bash-dublin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-ctencf-birthday-bash-dublin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Date: Aug 28, 6:00 – 9:30 PM @ Microsoft DublinJoin us for an exciting Meetup to celebrate 10 years of the Cloud Native &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Argo CD Up and Running: Cluster Management</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-argo-cd-up-and-running-cluster-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-argo-cd-up-and-running-cluster-management/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging session as we delve into &amp;lsquo;Argo CD: Up and Running&amp;rsquo; by Christian Hernandez and Andrew Block. Get &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Odesa Cloud Native #43: Performance Testing with GenAI</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-odesa-cloud-native-43-performance-testing-with-genai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-odesa-cloud-native-43-performance-testing-with-genai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Oleg Chornyi, &lt;a href="mailto:SRE@Airalo.Agenda"&gt;SRE@Airalo.Agenda&lt;/a&gt;:Srelock Holmes and Dr. Claude Watson: better togetherThe Elephant In The Room: &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KCD Colombia 2025</title><link>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-kcd-colombia-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/events/2025-08-28-kcd-colombia-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes Community Days (KCD) Colombia 2025, hosted in Bogotá on August 29, 2025, is the premier cloud-native and open&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Metal3.io becomes a CNCF incubating project</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-27-metal3-io-becomes-a-cncf-incubating-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-27-metal3-io-becomes-a-cncf-incubating-project/</guid><description>What is Metal3. io? Key Milestones and Ecosystem Growth Integrations Across the Cloud Native Landscape Technical Components Community Highlights Maintainer Perspective From the TOC Looking Ahead Posted on August 27, 2025 by Metal3. io Project Maintainers CNCF projects highlighted in this post The CNCF Technical Oversight Committee (TOC) has voted to accept Metal3. io as a CNCF incubating project. Metal3. io joins a growing ecosystem of technologies tackling real-world challenges at the edge of cloud native infrastructure. The Metal3. io project (pronounced: “Metal Kubed”) provides components for bare metal host management with Kubernetes. You can enroll your bare metal machines, provision operating system images, and then, if you like, deploy Kubernetes clusters to them. From there, operating and upgrading your Kubernetes clusters can be handled by Metal3. io. Moreover, Metal3.</description></item><item><title>How OCI Artifacts Will Drive Future AI Use Cases</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-27-how-oci-artifacts-will-drive-future-ai-use-cases/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-27-how-oci-artifacts-will-drive-future-ai-use-cases/</guid><description>The role of OCI artifacts in the AI ecosystem How Kubernetes and OCI Artifacts fit together CRI-O and OCI Artifact support Help to shape an AI native Kubernetes Posted on August 27, 2025 by Sascha Grunert, CNCF Member Project Maintainer (Graduate Project) CNCF | Special Interest Group (SIG) | CNCF Ambassador In recent years, the software industry has seen a strong shift toward enabling and supporting Artificial Intelligence (AI) workloads. While a variety of high level tools like Large Language Models (LLMs) already exist to support generic use cases, many domain specific solutions are either not yet available or come with significant development costs and risks, particularly when targeting more niche problems. This raises an important challenge: how can we avoid building a fragmented AI tooling landscape with limited real world applicability? To truly support the next wave of AI innovation, especially in cloud native environments, we need to rethink and reinforce our software component foundation. This includes standardizing formats, improving cross platform interoperability, and evolving Kubernetes with AI native features in mind. One of the most promising developments in this space revolves around Open Container Initiative (OCI) artifacts. OCI artifacts enable users to store and distribute arbitrary files and metadata using OCI compliant container registries. While originally used for generic purposes (like ORAS supports them), they’re now finding critical roles in AI/ML workflows, especially with the rise of specifications like the CNCF ModelPack. The CNCF ModelPack Specification builds on top of OCI artifacts and aims to standardize the packaging, distribution, and execution of AI models in cloud native environments. By moving away from proprietary formats, ModelPack facilitates reproducibility, portability, and vendor neutrality in machine learning workflows. This opens the door to several important use cases: Standardized AI/ML model packaging : With OCI artifacts, models can be versioned, distributed, and tracked like container images. This promotes consistency and traceability across environments. Secure model delivery : Well established solutions like sigstore signatures offer mechanisms to sign and verify OCI artifacts, improving model integrity and trustworthiness.</description></item><item><title>Use Envoy Gateway as the Unified Ingress Gateway and Waypoint Proxy for Ambient Mesh</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-26-use-envoy-gateway-as-the-unified-ingress-gateway-and-waypoint-proxy-for-ambient-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 13:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-26-use-envoy-gateway-as-the-unified-ingress-gateway-and-waypoint-proxy-for-ambient-/</guid><description>Why use Envoy Gateway with Ambient Mesh? How Envoy Gateway Works in Ambient Mesh? Setting Up Envoy Gateway as the Ingress Gateway Enabling Envoy Gateway as the Waypoint Proxy Should You Use Envoy Gateway with Ambient Mesh? What’s Next? References Posted on August 26, 2025 by Huabing (Robin) Zhao, Software Engineer &amp;amp; Ric Hincapié, DevOps and Support Engineer at Tetrate In this article, we’ll look at how you can use Envoy Gateway , an Envoy project open source solution, together with Istio when running in Ambient mode. This allows you to easily leverage the power of Envoy’s L7 capabilities for Ingress and east-west traffic in your mesh with easy-to-use CRDs. To understand how this integration works, let’s first take a quick look at Ambient Mesh itself. Also known as Istio Ambient mode , it’s a sidecar-less service mesh architecture that aims to simplify deployments and can boost efficiency for specific use cases. Unlike sidecar-based meshes, Ambient splits the data plane into two key components: the ztunnel , which secures service-to-service communication, and the Waypoint Proxy , which handles Layer 7 traffic routing and policy enforcement. On the other side, Envoy Gateway is a Kubernetes-native API gateway built on top of Envoy Proxy. It’s designed to work seamlessly with the Kubernetes Gateway API and takes a batteries-included approach—offering built-in support for authentication, authorization, rate limiting, CORS handling, header manipulation, and more. These capabilities are exposed through familiar Kubernetes-style APIs, letting you fully tap into Envoy’s power without needing complex configurations. Because both Ambient Mesh and Envoy Gateway are built on top of Envoy, they share a common foundation. This makes integration straightforward and allows Envoy Gateway to act as both the Ingress Gateway and Waypoint Proxy —giving you a consistent and powerful way to manage traffic and apply Layer 7 policies across your mesh. While Ambient Mesh simplifies service mesh operations by removing sidecars, its feature set doesn’t yet match the maturity of the sidecar-based model. Some advanced Layer 7 capabilities are either missing, considered experimental, or require extra complexity to configure in native Ambient mode.</description></item><item><title>How Should Prometheus Handle OpenTelemetry Resource Attributes? – A UX Research Report</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-25-how-should-prometheus-handle-opentelemetry-resource-attributes-a-ux-research-rep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 19:42:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-25-how-should-prometheus-handle-opentelemetry-resource-attributes-a-ux-research-rep/</guid><description>Project background Research approach User interviews insights Survey insights What I didn’t expect to learn (but did) Recommended solutions Short-term solutions Long-term vision Acknowledgments What’s next for me Posted on August 25, 2025 by Victoria Nduka, User Experience Designer CNCF projects highlighted in this post On May 29th, 2025, I wrapped up my mentorship with Prometheus through the Linux Foundation Mentorship Program. My project focused on understanding how Prometheus handles OpenTelemetry resource attributes and how that experience could be improved for users. My job was to conduct user research to get the user perspective on this challenge. In three months, I conducted user and stakeholder interviews, ran a survey, and analyzed the findings. In this article, I’ll share how I conducted the research, what I uncovered and where the communities involved could go from here. OpenTelemetry (OTel) has something called a resource attribute, which is extra information about the source of a metric, like the service, host, or environment that generated it. Prometheus, a time-series database, uses labels to identify and query metrics. If resource attributes are converted to labels, they can cause what’s known as “a cardinality explosion”, essentially creating too many unique combinations that overwhelm the system. This usually happens if the attributes change often or include a lot of unique values, like user IDs or pod names. Currently, there are three main approaches to handling this challenge: Map all resource attributes to labels: This creates cardinality explosion problems, especially for applications with large numbers of attributes or frequently changing attribute values. Selective promotion: Users manually choose which resource attributes are important enough to be converted to labels in Prometheus. Target info pattern: Put all resource attributes in a separate metric called target_info.</description></item><item><title>How I Team Up with GenAI to Craft Conference Talk Proposals</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-22-how-i-team-up-with-genai-to-craft-conference-talk-proposals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 20:09:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-22-how-i-team-up-with-genai-to-craft-conference-talk-proposals/</guid><description>An Incomplete List of GenAI Tells My Process Step One: Brainstorm Buddy Step Two: Shape the Story Step Three: Write the Abstract Prompt 1: Brainstorm Buddy Prompt 2: Shape the Story Prompt 3: Write the Abstract Enjoy the Result! Before you Submit LMKWYT! References Posted on August 22, 2025 by Whitney Lee, CNCF Ambassador and Senior Technical Advocate at Datadog TL;DR: GenAI can help you write conference abstracts, but if you use it without injecting your own curiosity and humanness, reviewers can tell. This post walks through my personal process for co-writing abstracts with GenAI in a way that preserves my voice and experience. I developed this process for technical talks, but it adapts well to other formats too. I’ve spoken at a lot of conferences, big and small. I’ve given keynotes. Breakouts. Workshops. I’ve been around the block and written many conference talk proposals. I’ve also been on program committees and reviewed others’ proposals. There’s always room for improvement, but I like to think I know what good is. In my view, here are some elements of a good talk proposal: – A clear, engaging idea (or a run-of-the-mill idea with a compelling angle) – Some clear details about the talk, like concrete examples or stories, or talk format and tools covered – Clear audience – Clear takeaways As you can imagine, the widespread use of GenAI to generate talk proposals has changed the game for both submitters and reviewers. As a submitter, you can type just one line into ChatGPT, for example: Write me a KubeCon + CloudNativeCon talk abstract on Validating Admission Policy And it produces something that, on the surface, looks pretty good!* Title: Enforcing What Matters: Building Safer Kubernetes with Validating Admission Policies Abstract: As Kubernetes adoption continues to grow across organizations, ensuring workloads meet security, compliance, and operational standards before hitting the cluster is more critical than ever.</description></item><item><title>Celebrating 100 Golden Kubestronauts</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-21-celebrating-100-golden-kubestronauts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-21-celebrating-100-golden-kubestronauts/</guid><description>What is a Golden Kubestronaut? Once a Golden, Always a Golden Growing Together as a Community Thank You! Posted on August 21, 2025 by Christophe Sauthier, Cloud Native Training and Certification Lead The Kubestronauts program has been growing at an incredible pace. We recently celebrated over 2000 kubestronauts across the globe, and today we’re excited to celebrate another milestone: over 100 Golden Kubestronauts have achieved Golden status in less than five months, thanks to their dedication and hard work. One of the most inspiring aspects of the Golden Kubestronauts community is its global reach. With more than 100 Golden badges earned so far, we see representation from every corner of the world—spanning North and South America, Europe, Asia, and beyond. From Austria, Brazil, and Canada to India, Japan, and Singapore , and from Germany, the Netherlands, France and the United States to places like Bangladesh, Mongolia, and Vietnam , Golden Kubestronauts truly embody the global spirit of CNCF. This diversity highlights not only the worldwide adoption of cloud native technologies, but also the strength of a community that learns, grows, and achieves together—regardless of geography. Becoming a Golden Kubestronaut is the highest level of recognition in the program. It requires completing all CNCF certifications as well as the Linux Foundation Certified Sysadmin (LFCS). Starting October 15th, the Certified Cloud Native Platform Engineering Associate (CNPA) will also be added as part of this journey—just as all future CNCF certifications will be included as the program continues to evolve. Golden Kubestronauts are proof of what’s possible when passion, knowledge, persistence, and a love of cloud native come together. They embody the breadth of skills across the ecosystem, from Kubernetes administration to observability, security, platform engineering, and more. It’s important to highlight that once you’ve earned Golden Kubestronaut status, it’s yours for life.</description></item><item><title>Uniting the Cloud Native Community at the Inaugural KCD SF Bay Area</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-20-uniting-the-cloud-native-community-at-the-inaugural-kcd-sf-bay-area/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-20-uniting-the-cloud-native-community-at-the-inaugural-kcd-sf-bay-area/</guid><description>Posted on August 20, 2025 by Lisa-Marie Namphy and Matthew Cascio, CNCF Ambassadors The cloud native landscape is constantly evolving, and staying ahead of the curve means more than just reading documentation—it means connecting with the people who are shaping the future. That’s exactly what the inaugural Kubernetes Community Day (KCD) SF Bay Area event is all about. This full-day gathering, proudly sponsored by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF), is the ultimate opportunity for enthusiasts, developers, and industry leaders to come together for a day of insightful talks and unparalleled networking. On September 9th , the historic Computer History Museum in Mountain View will open its doors to the Bay Area’s thriving cloud native community. This isn’t just a conference; it’s a celebration of collaboration and knowledge sharing. As an added bonus, your event registration grants you access to the museum’s fascinating exhibits, allowing you to explore the history of technology during your breaks. The KCD SF Bay Area event boasts an incredible lineup of speakers and visionaries. You’ll have the chance to hear directly from some of the most influential minds in the cloud native space. Confirmed speakers include: Solomon Hykes , the founder of Docker and Dagger. io, whose work has fundamentally changed the way we build and deploy applications. Jim Bugwadia , founder of Nirmata and a key maintainer of the popular policy engine Kyverno. Ramiro Berrelleza , founder of Okteto, who is dedicated to simplifying cloud native development workflows.</description></item><item><title>Celebrating 100 Days of Kagent</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-19-celebrating-100-days-of-kagent/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-19-celebrating-100-days-of-kagent/</guid><description>Accepted into CNCF as a sandbox project 🌟 100 Contributors &amp;amp; 1000+ GitHub Stars! Users advocating for kagent Talk to Infrastructure using kagent, A2A, kgateway and others! Integrate kagent with Argo MCP server Integrate kagent with home labs and MCP servers Use kagent for AI reliability engineering Fast delivery with kagent: A2A agent with discord: GCP terraform agent on kagent: 🌍 Kagent travels around the world 📢KubeCon + CloudNativeCon EU 2025 🇫🇷 GOSIM AI Paris 2025 🤠 KCD Texas 2025 🇬🇧London DevOps Meetup May 2025 🇨🇳KubeCon + CloudNativeCon China 2025 🇯🇵 OpenSSF Community – Japan 🇺🇸Open Source Summit NA Beyond cloud native operations 🎉 Wrapping up Posted on August 19, 2025 by Lin Sun, VP of Open Source at Solo. io CNCF projects highlighted in this post When we first introduced kagent on March 17th, 2025, we had a bold vision: to bring agentic AI to cloud native—empowering platforms and DevOps engineers to harness AI agents for solving real operational challenges. Fast forward 100 days, and today we’re celebrating a major milestone: 100 days of the kagent project ! 🎉Thank you everyone for being part of this journey! 🚀 What began as a tool to address our own customer challenges has grown into a thriving open-source project. Kagent is now a CNCF Sandbox project , and it’s evolving into a powerful declarative agentic AI framework —enabling like-minded engineers to run AI agents in Kubernetes, automating complex operations and streamlining troubleshooting workflows. Source: LinkedIn post In just 100 days, kagent has hit two incredible milestones: 🚀 100 contributors , with over 85% from outside Solo. io ⭐ 1000+ GitHub stars from our amazing community! We’ve been actively connecting with contributors through GitHub, Discord, weekly community calls, livestreams, and Contributor Spotlights. We’re incredibly grateful for everyone who’s explored, supported, and contributed to kagent. A huge shoutout to our top 20 contributors , and a special thanks to our top 3 : @eitanya, @peterj, and @sbx03 — we deeply appreciate your dedication and impact!! 🙌 Source: https://kagent. devstats. cncf. io/d/66/developer-activity-counts-by-companies?orgId=1 Over the past 100 days, we’ve been blown away by how our early adopters are using kagent in creative and powerful ways—including in production environments ! Across social media, community meetings , and beyond, users are not just experimenting—they’re innovating. 💡 Here are just a few examples of how the community is putting kagent to work: Source: Linkedin post Source: Linkedin post Source: LinkedIn post Source: LinkedIn post Source: LinkedIn post Source: LinkedIn post In just 100 days, kagent has made its mark on the global stage.</description></item><item><title>Combining GenAI &amp; Agentic AI to build scalable, autonomous systems</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-18-combining-genai-agentic-ai-to-build-scalable-autonomous-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-18-combining-genai-agentic-ai-to-build-scalable-autonomous-systems/</guid><description>Understanding Agentic AI GenAI is great at creation, while Agentic AI brings decision-making and execution Strategic considerations for tech leaders Posted on August 18, 2025 by Marta Fernandes, Engineering Operations Manager, YLD A common pattern in today’s AI adoption is that businesses are investing heavily in GenAI capabilities, yet many are leaving significant value on the table by failing to pair it with Agentic AI. This matters because while GenAI can generate content, ideas, or responses, it can’t act on them. However, when combined with Agentic AI, your systems shift from being reactive and prompt-driven to autonomous and outcome-oriented. This article aims to help senior technology leaders better understand the value Agentic AI can add to existing AI infrastructure, while outlining key considerations to determine whether its implementation aligns with your business needs. Image caption: Core components of an Agentic AI Architecture from Markovate. Agentic AI systems are designed to operate autonomously, perceiving their environment, making decisions, and executing actions without continuous human oversight. This autonomy enables businesses to streamline operations, reduce costs, and enhance scalability. The image above illustrates how the following systems function: Perception layer: This layer involves collecting data from various sources i. e. sensors, cameras, microphones, and digital inputs, to understand the current state of the environment. For businesses, this means real-time monitoring of operations, customer interactions, and market trends, facilitating proactive decision-making and rapid response to changing conditions. Cognition layer: Once data is collected, the cognition layer processes this information to interpret context, recognise patterns, and determine the best course of action.</description></item><item><title>Gear Up for the 5th Annual KCD Washington DC!</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-16-gear-up-for-the-5th-annual-kcd-washington-dc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 13:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-16-gear-up-for-the-5th-annual-kcd-washington-dc/</guid><description>Posted on August 16, 2025 by Matthew Cascio, CNCF Ambassador and KCD Washington DC Organizer We’re so thrilled to be organizing another year of cloud native community in the Nation’s Capital. Past years have witnessed amazing presentations ranging from core Kubernetes topics to emerging trends in ML/AI, sustainability, virtual clusters and more. This year promises to be even more amazing. Our program is set, and includes two new innovations for our KCD: For the first time, we’re offering a hands-on workshop covering basic and intermediate topics on using Prometheus in your observability practice. The curriculum covers 20-25% of the Linux Foundation’s Prometheus Certified Associate (PCA) course. While this workshop does not lead to certification, and is not a substitute for the PCA course, it will give you a solid working knowledge for getting started and perhaps help you decide if you’d like to pursue certification separately – if you do, you’ll be ahead of the game with this solid foundation. We’re adding a government-focused cybersecurity keynote by our special guest, Ashley Jones, Cybersecurity Advisor for Region III of the Department of Homeland Security, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA. ) Special Government &amp;amp; Cybersecurity Focus – and free admission for our government employee community members! You won’t want to miss Ashley Jones’ keynote if you’re a cybersecurity professional or involved in government technology in any way. A limited number of free tickets will be available soon for our community members working for federal, state or local government agencies. You can request a free government ticket here: https://forms. gle/aLNfRwpvFn3vQ5Vo8 Plus our regular program is amazing! All of that rests on top of our regular program that includes presentations like: Industry perspective: Scaling Cloud Native: Reaching the Next 10 Million Users by Lin Sun at Solo. io K8s in the Enterprise: From Silos to SIGs: Building Kubernetes Community in the Enterprise by Jason Stryker Inclusivity: Unleash Your Inner Ally: Let’s Make Open Source Radically Welcoming! by Catherine Paganini and Christopher Khanoyan advocate for inclusivity in open source.</description></item></channel></rss>