<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Openshift on Kubermates</title><link>https://kubermates.org/tags/openshift/</link><description>Recent content in Openshift on Kubermates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 07:54:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kubermates.org/tags/openshift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.13</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-25-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 07:54:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-25-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-13/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>Disaster Recovery: Achieving Instantaneous Hot-Hot with OpenShift</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-20-disaster-recovery-achieving-instantaneous-hot-hot-with-openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-20-disaster-recovery-achieving-instantaneous-hot-hot-with-openshift/</guid><description>Share The biggest challenge for disaster recovery in traditional environments is that every environment looks and feels different. If you&amp;rsquo;re moving from a colo that someone manages to VMware, the cloud, or a different VMware data center, they all look and feel different. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re using the same virtualization provider, storage is probably handled differently. There has to be a lot of planning and strategy around how to copy data from one area to another since that’s not something natively built into your virtualization provider. You also have to figure out networking, DNS, routing, etc. With Red Hat OpenShift , all of these components are software-defined. You get software-defined DNS, networking, and storage layers all because it’s based on Kubernetes. Out-of-the-box OpenShift won’t “automagically” failover without additional levels of configuration, much like VMware or other traditional infrastructure environments. But the tools required are mostly there for you, either pre-packaged and open-source or robustly tested and a standard in the space. You can set up OpenShift in any environment because the least common denominator for everything, no matter where you are (bare metal or virtual), is the operating system This is where OpenShift lives. That’s why it is the perfect tool for building a truly agile infrastructure that can move freely between environments, providing instantaneous disaster recovery for businesses. There are different benefits of infrastructure agility.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.12</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-11-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:51:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-11-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-12/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Named a Leader in 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management for the Third Consecutive Year</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-11-red-hat-named-a-leader-in-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-container-management-f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-11-red-hat-named-a-leader-in-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-container-management-f/</guid><description>Share This week we announced that for the third consecutive year, Red Hat has been named a Leader in the Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Container Management. We’re thrilled by this recognition and believe it represents continued validation of Red Hat OpenShift’s strong execution and strategy for delivering an industry leading application platform across hybrid environments from the data center, to the cloud, and to the edge. Red Hat OpenShift is recognized for its ability to execute and completeness of vision. Red Hat’s investments in OpenShift as a platform for AI workloads, and in building AI capabilities directly into the product to make users’ jobs easier. We believe it is also reflected in Red Hat’s position in the Gartner Magic Quadrant. OpenShift provides a comprehensive application platform with container management capabilities, including support for virtual machine workloads and AI-powered services. Magic Quadrant reports are a culmination of rigorous, fact-based research in specific markets, providing a wide-angle view of the relative positions of the providers in markets where growth is high and provider differentiation is distinct. Providers are positioned into four quadrants: Leaders, Challengers, Visionaries and Niche Players. Leaders execute well against their current vision and are well positioned for tomorrow. The research enables you to get the most from market analysis in alignment with your unique business and technology needs. Gartner defines container management as offerings that support the deployment and operation of containerized workloads and associated resources. It uses a combination of technologies (many open source) that enable agile application deployments and infrastructure modernization.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.11</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-10-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-08-10-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-11/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>Red Hat Named a Leader in 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Cloud-Native Application Platforms for the Second Consecutive Year</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-07-red-hat-named-a-leader-in-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-cloud-native-applicati/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-07-red-hat-named-a-leader-in-2025-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-cloud-native-applicati/</guid><description>Share This week we announced that Red Hat has been positioned as a Leader for the second year in a row in the 2025 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for Cloud-Native Application Platforms. We are proud of this recognition, as we believe this is a strong validation of Red Hat OpenShift cloud services as a flexible, complete, and secure cloud-native application platform for AI-enabled applications and virtualized and containerized workloads across the hybrid cloud. The Red Hat OpenShift cloud services portfolio consists of jointly engineered solutions with hyperscalers, including Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS , Azure Red Hat OpenShift , Red Hat OpenShift on IBM Cloud and Red Hat OpenShift Dedicated on Google Cloud. Source: Gartner, “Magic Quadrant for Cloud-Native Application Platforms,” August 2025 To help further explain the evaluation of the Gartner Magic Quadrant from our point of view, we’re answering some of the most frequently asked questions. “Magic Quadrant reports are a culmination of rigorous, fact-based research in specific markets, providing a wide-angle view of the relative positions of the providers in markets where growth is high and provider differentiation is distinct. Providers are positioned into four quadrants: Leaders, Challengers, Visionaries and Niche Players. The research enables you to get the most from market analysis in alignment with your unique business and technology needs. ” “Gartner defines cloud-native application platforms as those that provide managed application runtime environments for applications and integrated capabilities to manage the life cycle of an application or application component. They typically enable distributed application deployments and support cloud style operations — such as elasticity, multitenancy and self-service — without requiring the development team to provision infrastructure or manage containers. Cloud-native application platforms are designed to facilitate the deployment, runtime execution, and management of modern cloud-native or cloud-optimized applications without the need to manage any underlying infrastructure. Also, they are designed to enhance developer productivity, accelerate development and deployment cycles, and increase operational effectiveness by making it easier to scale on demand. Cloud-native application platforms offer a structured execution environment for applications, effectively hiding the complexities of the underlying infrastructure and computing resources.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 articles Red Hat customers are reading right now</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-07-top-10-articles-red-hat-customers-are-reading-right-now/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-07-top-10-articles-red-hat-customers-are-reading-right-now/</guid><description>Share Staying on top of the latest advancements in open source technology is more critical than ever. At Red Hat, we&amp;rsquo;re at the forefront of this innovation, continuously delivering solutions that empower enterprises to navigate complex challenges, encourage efficiency, and build a more secure future. In this roundup, our customers and communities have been particularly drawn to topics spanning the future of AI in IT, the ongoing evolution of our core platforms, and the strategic shifts in critical industries like telecommunications. From groundbreaking product releases that enhance virtualization and accelerate AI workloads to essential insights on security, developer productivity, and sovereign cloud, these articles offer a pulse on what&amp;rsquo;s driving the open hybrid cloud. Explore the top stories that are shaping the future of enterprise IT and empowering you to innovate with confidence. Red Hat OpenShift 4. 19, now generally available, is designed to propel your enterprise forward in the AI era while offering enhanced flexibility for virtualization and security. This release, built on Kubernetes 1. 32 and CRI-O 1. 32, brings powerful capabilities to the trusted OpenShift application platform. From dynamic GPU slicing to accelerated expertise with Red Hat OpenShift Lightspeed, OpenShift 4. 19 provides the comprehensive and consistent foundation needed to innovate faster across your hybrid cloud environment without compromising on security.</description></item><item><title>Introducing OpenShift Service Mesh 3.1</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-05-introducing-openshift-service-mesh-3-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-05-introducing-openshift-service-mesh-3-1/</guid><description>Share Red Hat OpenShift Service Mesh 3. 1 has been released and is included with the Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform and Red Hat OpenShift Platform Plus. Based on the Istio, Envoy, and Kiali projects, this release updates the version of Istio to 1. 26 and Kiali to 2. 11 , and is supported on OpenShift Container Platform 4. 16 and above. This is the first minor release following Red Hat OpenShift Service Mesh 3. 0, a major update to converge OpenShift Service Mesh with the community Istio project, with installation and management using the Sail operator. This change helps ensure that OpenShift Service Mesh can offer the latest stable Istio features with Red Hat support. If you are running OpenShift Service Mesh 2. 6 or earlier releases, you must upgrade to OpenShift Service Mesh 3. 0 before upgrading to 3.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.10</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-29-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-29-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-10/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.9</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-22-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 21:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-22-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-9/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.8</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-15-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 20:59:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-15-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-8/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.7</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-08-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-08-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-7/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.6</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-01-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:03:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-07-01-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-6/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.5</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-06-24-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:02:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-06-24-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-5/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item><item><title>4.20.0-okd-scos.ec.4</title><link>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-06-19-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/releases/2025-06-19-4-20-0-okd-scos-ec-4/</guid><description>These archives contain the client tooling for OKD on CentOS Stream CoreOS. To verify the contents of this directory, use the &amp;lsquo;gpg&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;shasum&amp;rsquo; tools to ensure the archives you have downloaded match those published from this location. The openshift-install binary has been preconfigured to install the following release: There was an error while loading. Please reload this page. There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.</description></item></channel></rss>