<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kodekloud on Kubermates</title><link>https://kubermates.org/tags/kodekloud/</link><description>Recent content in Kodekloud on Kubermates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kubermates.org/tags/kodekloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kubernetes Tutorial for Beginners 2025</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-23-kubernetes-tutorial-for-beginners-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-23-kubernetes-tutorial-for-beginners-2025/</guid><description>Introduction - Why Learn Kubernetes in 2025 Why Kubernetes Is Worth Your Time Why 2025 Is the Perfect Time to Learn What Is Kubernetes? (Quick Refresher) Understanding the Basics How Kubernetes Solves Real Problems Ready to Get Hands-On? Understanding Kubernetes Architecture (The Foundation) The Control Plane (The Brain of Kubernetes) The Worker Nodes (Where Your Apps Live) Putting It All Together Learn Visually Your First Kubernetes Setup (Getting Started the Right Way) Option 1: Run Kubernetes Locally (Minikube or Kind) Option 2: Learn Kubernetes Online Instantly (No Setup Needed) Option 3: Cloud-Based Kubernetes (Intermediate Path) Best Practice for 2025 Beginners Step-by-Step Kubernetes Tutorial for Beginners 2025 Step 1: Create a Namespace (Optional but Recommended) Step 2: Deploy Your First Pod Step 3: Expose the Pod as a Service Step 4: Scale Your Deployment Step 5: Clean Up (Always Good Practice) What You Just Learned Best Way to Learn Kubernetes Online Start with the Fundamentals Follow a Beginner-Friendly Roadmap Why KodeKloud Is the Best Place to Learn Kubernetes Online Pro Tip: Combine Study + Practice From Beginner to Certified - Your Next Step Why Get Certified in Kubernetes Popular Kubernetes Certifications How KodeKloud Helps You Get Certified Common Mistakes Beginners Make (and How to Avoid Them) 1. Skipping the Fundamentals 2. Avoiding YAML and Declarative Configuration 3. Overcomplicating the Setup 4. Ignoring the ‘Why’ Behind the Commands 5. Not Practicing Troubleshooting Key Takeaway Free &amp;amp; Paid Resources to Learn Kubernetes 1. Free Kubernetes Resources 2. Paid Kubernetes Resources 3. When to Move from Free to Paid Learning Summary - Why 2025 Is the Best Time to Start Why Start Learning Now Final Thought FAQ CKA Exam Verification Guide Kubernetes Architecture Explained: Nodes, Pods, and Clusters Quick Fixes for Common Kubernetes Issues Guide to AWS Certification What is Kubernetes? A Beginner’s Guide to Container Orchestration DevOps Tutorials 2025: Step-by-Step Learning Resources for Beginners Ubuntu: Set Timezone How to Enable SSH on Ubuntu Certifications in DevOps: Which Are Worth Your Time in 2025? What is DevOps? Understand Kubernetes architecture step by step - Control Plane, Nodes, Pods, and Clusters. Start instantly with KodeKloud Free Kubernetes Labs - no installation or setup needed. Learn Kubernetes online through KodeKloud Kubernetes courses , visual lessons, and browser-based labs. Follow a proven learning roadmap covering YAML, Deployments, Services, and troubleshooting.</description></item><item><title>CKA Exam Verification Guide</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-19-cka-exam-verification-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 11:51:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-19-cka-exam-verification-guide/</guid><description>Exam Setup - The Speed Booster (Optional, But Highly Recommended!) Should you set this up? Good news about autocomplete: The time-saving aliases: Why these specific aliases? Configure vim for YAML editing: Author&amp;rsquo;s recommendation: 1. Storage (10% of the exam) StorageClass Verification Dynamic Provisioning Test PV/PVC Binding Access Modes &amp;amp; Reclaim Policies 2. Troubleshooting (30% of exam) Cluster Health Node Diagnostics Control Plane Components etcd Health Resource Monitoring Container Logs Service Troubleshooting 3. Workloads &amp;amp; Scheduling (15% of exam) Deployments Rolling Updates &amp;amp; Rollbacks ConfigMaps &amp;amp; Secrets HPA (Horizontal Pod Autoscaler) Probes Resource Limits Node Affinity &amp;amp; Taints Cluster Architecture (25% of exam) RBAC Infrastructure Preparation kubeadm Cluster Cluster Upgrade High Availability Helm &amp;amp; Kustomize Extension Interfaces Services &amp;amp; Networking (20% of exam) Pod Connectivity Service Validation Service Types Network Policies Ingress Gateway API DNS Imperative Commands &amp;amp; Time-Savers Generate YAML (Most Important!) kubectl explain (2x faster than docs!) Quick Creation Patterns Exam Workflow Step-by-step process: Time Management Real-World Troubleshooting Scenarios Scenario 1: Pod Stuck in Pending Scenario 2: CrashLoopBackOff Scenario 3: Service Not Accessible Scenario 4: Node NotReady Scenario 5: Deployment Rollout Stuck Scenario 6: PVC Stuck in Pending Common Verification Patterns Quick Reference Card Success Checklist Final Preparation Tips Common Mistakes to Avoid FAQ Kubernetes Architecture Explained: Nodes, Pods, and Clusters Quick Fixes for Common Kubernetes Issues Guide to AWS Certification What is Kubernetes? A Beginner’s Guide to Container Orchestration DevOps Tutorials 2025: Step-by-Step Learning Resources for Beginners Ubuntu: Set Timezone How to Enable SSH on Ubuntu Certifications in DevOps: Which Are Worth Your Time in 2025? What is DevOps? Setup: Use aliases ( k , $do , $now ) only if you’ve practiced them. k $do $now YAML Tip: Generate with &amp;ndash;dry-run=client -o yaml ; never write from scratch. &amp;ndash;dry-run=client -o yaml Docs Shortcut: Use kubectl explain , not web docs. kubectl explain Verify Everything: Always get , describe , logs , and check Events. get describe logs Storage: Default StorageClass + PV/PVC binding must work. Troubleshooting: Start from nodes → system pods → workloads. RBAC &amp;amp; Security: Test permissions with kubectl auth can-i. kubectl auth can-i Upgrade Flow: Control plane first, then kubelet restart. Networking: Endpoints tell truth; check DNS/CoreDNS if service fails.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Architecture Explained: Nodes, Pods, and Clusters</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-16-kubernetes-architecture-explained-nodes-pods-and-clusters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:53:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-16-kubernetes-architecture-explained-nodes-pods-and-clusters/</guid><description>Introduction: Understanding the Heart of Kubernetes What Is Kubernetes Architecture? (Big Picture Overview) The Kubernetes Cluster - The Foundation How the Cluster Works Key Traits of a Kubernetes Cluster Why the Cluster Matters Control Plane Components - The Brain of Kubernetes 1. API Server - The Front Door of the Cluster 2. etcd - The Cluster’s Memory 3. Scheduler - The Decision Maker 4. Controller Manager - The Cluster’s Automation Engine How These Components Work Together Worker Node Components - The Hands of Kubernetes 1. Kubelet - The Node’s Local Agent 2. Kube-Proxy - The Network Manager 3. Container Runtime - The Engine Running the Containers How Worker Nodes Fit into Kubernetes Architecture Why Worker Nodes Matter Pods - The Smallest Unit of Deployment What Is a Pod? How Pods Work Pods and Networking Pods, Nodes, and the Bigger Picture Why Pods Matter How Kubernetes Works - Step-by-Step Workflow Step 1: Defining the Desired State Step 2: API Server Processes the Request Step 3: Scheduler Assigns Pods to Nodes Step 4: Kubelet Creates and Monitors Pods Step 5: Kube-Proxy Manages Networking Step 6: Controller Manager Ensures Desired State Step 7: Scaling, Updates, and Maintenance In Short: How Kubernetes Works Master Node vs Worker Node - Key Differences Master Node - The Control Center Worker Node - The Execution Layer Master Node vs Worker Node - Comparison Table How They Work Together Why This Design Matters Visualizing Kubernetes Architecture (KodeKloud Tip) Visualizing the Cluster Structure Learn by Seeing and Doing FAQs Quick Fixes for Common Kubernetes Issues Guide to AWS Certification What is Kubernetes? A Beginner’s Guide to Container Orchestration DevOps Tutorials 2025: Step-by-Step Learning Resources for Beginners Ubuntu: Set Timezone How to Enable SSH on Ubuntu Certifications in DevOps: Which Are Worth Your Time in 2025? What is DevOps? Understand the difference between master node vs worker node and their unique roles. Explore how Kubernetes components like API Server, Scheduler, and Kubelet communicate. Discover how Kubernetes works to deploy, scale, and self-heal applications automatically. Visualize the entire Kubernetes cluster architecture - nodes, Pods, and communication flow. Master the fundamentals of container orchestration through KodeKloud’s free Kubernetes labs.</description></item><item><title>What is Kubernetes? A Beginner’s Guide to Container Orchestration</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-10-what-is-kubernetes-a-beginner-s-guide-to-container-orchestration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-10-10-what-is-kubernetes-a-beginner-s-guide-to-container-orchestration/</guid><description>Introduction: Why Everyone’s Talking About Kubernetes Understanding Containers - The Foundation of Kubernetes What Are Containers? Containers vs. Virtual Machines (VMs) Why Containers Changed Everything Learn Containers the Hands-On Way The Problem Before Kubernetes - When Containers Got Out of Hand When Containers Multiply The Need for Orchestration The Birth of Kubernetes Before and After Kubernetes (At a Glance) What is Kubernetes? Kubernetes in Simple Terms Kubernetes as a Declarative System Core Building Blocks of Kubernetes A Quick Example How Kubernetes Works - The Big Picture The Control Plane - The Brain of Kubernetes The Worker Nodes - The Hands of Kubernetes How It All Works Together (Simplified Flow) Core Kubernetes Concepts (Explained Simply) 1. Pods - The Smallest Unit of Work 2. ReplicaSets - Keeping the Right Number of Pods Alive 3. Deployments - The Smart Way to Manage Pods 4. Services - Connecting Everything Together 5. ConfigMaps and Secrets - Managing App Configurations 6. Namespaces - Organizing Your Cluster 7. Ingress (Bonus for Beginners) Why Use Kubernetes? (Key Benefits Explained Simply) 1. Automated Scaling - Grow or Shrink on Demand 2. Self-Healing - Applications That Fix Themselves 3. Seamless Updates and Rollbacks 4.</description></item><item><title>Certifications in DevOps: Which Are Worth Your Time in 2025?</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-09-29-certifications-in-devops-which-are-worth-your-time-in-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:52:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-09-29-certifications-in-devops-which-are-worth-your-time-in-2025/</guid><description>The Certification Market in 2025: Why It’s Different Cloud Certifications: The Foundation Layer You Can’t Skip Kubernetes: The Practical Core of DevOps Infrastructure as Code: Terraform as the Lingua Franca CI/CD: From Jenkins to GitHub Actions and GitLab Pipelines Linux: The Silent Backbone of DevOps The Maturity Layer: Security, Reliability, and Cost Security: Proving You Can Ship Safely Reliability: From DevOps to SRE Cost Optimization: Enter FinOps Why This Layer Matters Observability: From Luxury to Necessity Strategic Roadmaps: Picking the Right Path Roadmap 1: Beginners Entering DevOps Roadmap 2: Sysadmin to SRE/Platform Engineer Roadmap 3: Developer to DevOps Engineer Why Roadmaps Work Final Word: Proof That Matters FAQ What is DevOps? Kubernetes = Core Skill → CKA, CKAD, and CKS prove real, hands-on expertise. Over 3,000 jobs explicitly ask for them. Terraform = IaC Standard → Terraform Associate (003) dominates; 15k+ U. S. job postings mention it. CI/CD Has Shifted → Jenkins is legacy; GitHub Actions &amp;amp; GitLab certifications are the new benchmarks. Linux = Bedrock → LFCS, RHCSA, RHCE remain evergreen. 10k+ jobs still require Linux fluency. Maturity Layer Matters → Security (CKS, AWS Security Specialty), Reliability (Google DevOps Engineer), and Cost (FOCP) now separate leaders from juniors. Observability = No Longer Optional → Grafana/Prometheus certifications validate modern monitoring and tracing. Certifications = Multipliers, Not Magic → They amplify hands-on skills and career progression; 81% of certified pros report better job opportunities. Picture this: it’s spring 2025, and you’re sitting in an interview for a mid-to-senior DevOps engineer role.</description></item><item><title>Best DevOps Courses in 2025: Learning Paths to Boost Your Career</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-09-16-best-devops-courses-in-2025-learning-paths-to-boost-your-career/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:19:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-09-16-best-devops-courses-in-2025-learning-paths-to-boost-your-career/</guid><description>2025-ready skills - IT Foundations &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Linux &amp;amp; Networking &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Git &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Containers &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Kubernetes &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; CI/CD &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; IaC &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; GitOps &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Observability &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Security &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Platform Engineering &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Cloud &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; AI. AI everywhere - LLMs, MCPs, RAG, anomaly detection, and copilots are now part of daily DevOps workflows. Hands-on learning - every step mapped to KodeKloud’s lab-first courses, and real projects. Clear role tracks - follow one of four paths: DevOps Engineer, Site Reliability Engineer, Platform Engineer, or Cloud-Dev. Milestone projects - practical, production-like capstones to showcase on GitHub and in interviews. Free AI Week - start with the exclusive 5-Day AI Learning Path to build confidence with modern AI skills. DevOps in 2025 is no longer about “tools-first. ” Teams are building reliable platforms that support fast delivery and strong governance. At the same time, AI is becoming a core part of the workflow -from writing Kubernetes manifests to detecting anomalies in observability dashboards. The expectations are broader: Production fundamentals (Linux, networking, shell, Git) are non‑negotiable. Cloud-native skills (containers, Kubernetes, service meshes, Gateway API) are baseline. IaC + GitOps is how infra/app changes land in prod-repeatably, auditor‑friendly.</description></item><item><title>Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-15-why-kubecon-india-2025-meant-more-to-kodekloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 07:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-08-15-why-kubecon-india-2025-meant-more-to-kodekloud/</guid><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Landmark Partnership for India: CNCF + KodeKloud + Linux Foundation 2. A Special Conversation: Mumshad Meets Chris Aniszczyk, CTO of CNCF 3. Book Signing: Knowledge Meets Connection 4. Meeting the Faces Behind the Screens 5. Why KubeCon is a Networking Goldmine for Tech Professionals 6. Key Takeaways for Our Community Closing the Loop: Why This Year Matters Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! Brilliant. It’s exactly what KodeKloud is about. When attendees, speakers, and industry peers tell you that at KubeCon India, it’s a clear sign that what KodeKloud is doing is making a real impact. For KodeKloud, KubeCon India 2025 was more than a tech conference. It was a celebration of community, connection, and the power of practical learning in the Cloud Native space. From conversations with global leaders to meeting hundreds of learners face-to-face, this year meant more than ever before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description></item><item><title>From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-22-from-cfp-to-stage-win-your-tech-talk-slot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 06:19:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-22-from-cfp-to-stage-win-your-tech-talk-slot/</guid><description>Step 1: It All Starts with the &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; - Choosing Your Topic Step 2: The Title - Your Ten-Word Sales Pitch Step 3: The Abstract — The Heart of Your Proposal Step 4: The Details Matter — Track, Level, and Benefits Final Pro-Tip: Think Like a Reviewer Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! You find the perfect conference, open the Call for Proposals (CFP) form, and pour your heart into it. You hit &amp;ldquo;submit. &amp;quot; And then you wait… That rejection email always stings. We’ve all been there. But what if you could change the odds? What if you could move from hoping your talk gets chosen to expecting it? After speaking at numerous global conferences and analyzing hundreds of accepted and rejected talks, I’ve found that a winning proposal isn’t about luck. It’s about strategy. This guide will break down that strategy, making it applicable for any tech event, from a local Google Community Day to the global stages of KubeCon or a Linux Foundation Summit. Before you write a single word of your abstract, you need to pick the right topic. The best topics sit at the intersection of three things: It Solves a Painful, Urgent Problem: Reviewers are looking for talks that solve a real-world problem their audience is facing right now. A talk on “migrating to Kubernetes” was a guaranteed hit in 2019, but in 2025, the problem is no longer urgent. Conversely, a talk on “ securing a Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) system” is incredibly urgent today because it’s a new, complex technology with high stakes and few established best practices. Ask yourself: What are people complaining about on social media or in community Slacks? What new technology is causing both excitement and anxiety? That’s where you’ll find winning topics.</description></item><item><title>What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation!</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-15-what-is-kubernetes-finally-a-simple-explanation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:26:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-15-what-is-kubernetes-finally-a-simple-explanation/</guid><description>Why Do We Need Kubernetes? It&amp;rsquo;s Hard to Run a Large Number of Containers What Is Kubernetes Used For? Automation Doing a Lot with Very Few Instructions Sticking to the Plan You Provide What Is a Kubernetes Cluster? What Is a Pod in Kubernetes? Kubernetes vs. Docker Learn More about Kubernetes with a Beginner-Friendly Course Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? Well, you&amp;rsquo;re about to read something different. Finally, a blog that will explain &amp;ldquo;What is Kubernetes?&amp;rdquo; in very simple words ; an explanation for normal human beings. But Kubernetes is a solution to a problem. And to understand the solution, you first have to look at the problem it solves. Containers, containers, containers… in the voice of Steve Ballmer. You probably heard about Docker. But even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s no big deal to understand it. Docker is a set of tools that allow you to create, edit, and run containers. And a container is just an application in a small little box. What&amp;rsquo;s so cool about containers? Well, one thing is that the application has all that it needs (the so-called dependencies ) inside that little box. So you can take that container, run it on Windows, MacOS, Linux, whatever.</description></item><item><title>Quick Fixes for Common Kubernetes Issues</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-06-quick-fixes-for-common-kubernetes-issues/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 18:26:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-07-06-quick-fixes-for-common-kubernetes-issues/</guid><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CrashLoopBackOff — The Pod That Won’t Stay Alive 2. Pending Pods — Scheduling Never Happens 3. Service Not Routing to Pods 4. ImagePullBackOff / ErrImagePull — Container Won’t Start 5. Deployment Rollout Stuck 6. Secrets Visible in YAML — A Security Misstep 7. Port Forwarding Doesn’t Work 8. RBAC: Access Denied Quick Commands for Any Issue Final Thoughts: Embrace the Errors Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! The good news? You’re not alone. This guide walks you through the most common Kubernetes problems developers and DevOps teams face — and more importantly, how to fix them quickly. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to Kubernetes or scaling your first production app, consider this your essential cheat sheet. Symptoms: Your Pod starts, crashes, restarts, and repeats the loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Microservices</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-16-the-definitive-guide-to-microservices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 04:23:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-16-the-definitive-guide-to-microservices/</guid><description>Key Takeaways Understanding Microservices How Microservices Operate Key Components of Microservices Architecture Advantages of Microservices Common Design Patterns in Microservices Challenges and Criticisms of Microservices Microservices vs. Monolithic Architectures Migrating from Monolithic to Microservices Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) vs. Microservices Real-World Examples and Case Studies Tools and Technologies for Microservices Best Practices for Building Microservices Summary Frequently Asked Questions What are microservices, and how do they differ from monolithic architectures? How do microservices communicate with each other? What are some common design patterns used in microservices? What challenges can arise when adopting microservices? What tools and technologies are commonly used for building microservices? Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! They ensure scalability, flexibility, and ease of maintenance by allowing individual services to operate and be updated autonomously. In this guide, we will break down what microservices are, how they operate, their advantages, key components, and best practices, offering a comprehensive overview for anyone looking to understand this modern architectural approach. Microservices architecture allows applications to be built as a collection of independent, modular services that enhance scalability and flexibility. Key components of microservices include API gateways, service registries, and individual data stores for each service, which streamline communication and data management. While microservices offer advantages like fault isolation and faster development cycles, they also introduce complexity and require robust tools for management and orchestration. Microservices are an architectural style that organizes an application as a collection of small, independently deployable services. Unlike traditional monolithic architectures, where a single service encapsulates all functionalities, microservices based applications break down applications into individual services, each focusing on a specific business capability. This modularity allows for independent deployment and scaling, making microservice architecture a popular choice for modern applications, particularly when considering internal microservices. One of the key characteristics of microservices is their cloud-native approach. Each service operates independently but is part of a larger application framework, often utilizing cloud resources to ensure scalability and fault tolerance.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes HPA: Mastering Horizontal Pod Autoscaler Basics and Best Practices</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-15-kubernetes-hpa-mastering-horizontal-pod-autoscaler-basics-and-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 04:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-15-kubernetes-hpa-mastering-horizontal-pod-autoscaler-basics-and-best-practices/</guid><description>Key Takeaways Understanding Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA) How HPA Works Setting Up Metrics Server Configuring HPA in Your Kubernetes Cluster Practical Example: Implementing HPA Deploy Sample Application Create Kubernetes Service Apply Horizontal Pod Autoscaler Testing HPA Functionality Increase Load Monitor Scaling Events Decrease Load HPA Limitations Best Practices for HPA Configuration Integrating HPA with Other Autoscalers Usage and Cost Reporting Summary Frequently Asked Questions What is the primary purpose of the Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)? How does HPA determine the number of replicas to scale? What are some common limitations of HPA? How can integrating HPA with other autoscalers improve scaling efficiency? What tools can help track resource usage and manage costs in a Kubernetes cluster with HPA? Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! This capability ensures your application remains responsive and performs well under varying traffic loads. In this article, we will cover the basics of Kubernetes HPA, how it works, best practices, and a hands-on example to help you master this critical Kubernetes feature. The Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA) automatically adjusts the number of pod replicas in Kubernetes based on CPU and memory metrics, ensuring stable application performance under varying loads. Proper setup of the Metrics Server is essential, as it provides the necessary resource metrics for HPA to make informed scaling decisions; accurate HPA configuration specifies minimum and maximum replicas along with target utilization. Integrating HPA with other autoscalers such as the Vertical Pod Autoscaler (VPA) and Cluster Autoscaler enhances scaling strategies, allowing for efficient resource management and responsiveness to varying application demands. At its core, the Kubernetes Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA) is a Kubernetes resource that automatically adjusts the number of pod replicas based on observed CPU and memory usage metrics. This dynamic adjustment ensures your application maintains stable performance even as traffic fluctuates, making it a critical component for production workloads. Horizontal pod autoscaling HPA operates by continuously monitoring specified metrics and making scaling decisions to match the demand. The HPA utilizes resource metrics like CPU and memory, as well as custom metrics and cpu metrics, to determine the appropriate number of replicas needed. For example, if the average CPU utilization exceeds a predefined threshold, HPA will increase the number of replicas to distribute the load. Conversely, when the demand decreases, HPA reduces the number of replicas, optimizing resource usage and reducing costs. Additionally, the custom metrics api can be leveraged to enhance monitoring capabilities.</description></item><item><title>kubectl logs: How to Get Pod Logs in Kubernetes (With Examples)</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-14-kubectl-logs-how-to-get-pod-logs-in-kubernetes-with-examples/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 14:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-14-kubectl-logs-how-to-get-pod-logs-in-kubernetes-with-examples/</guid><description>Prerequisites Create a Pod How to View Pod Logs View Pod logs in real time Fetch a specific number of lines of Pod logs View logs of an exited container Fetch Pod logs from a specific time period Fetch the logs of a specific container in a multi-container Pod Conclusion Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! Like any software, these applications can sometimes fail or not perform as expected due to various reasons. When such failures occur, it’s important to identify and rectify the issue quickly. One key aspect of troubleshooting involves analyzing the application logs, which can provide valuable information about the root cause of the problem. Logs are essentially records of events happening within your application. By examining these logs, we can often gain insights into what went wrong. In this blog post, we’ll learn how to access Pod logs in Kubernetes using the kubectl logs command. Note that when we say Pod logs, we’re generally referring to the logs of the applications running in containers inside the Pod. kubectl logs To easily follow along with the examples in this post, we recommend using KodeKloud’s Kubernetes playground. This playground will provide you instant access to a running Kubernetes cluster with kubectl already installed. No need for you to install any software. With just one click, you&amp;rsquo;ll be ready to run the example code snippets and start experimenting right away. kubectl Alternatively, if you prefer to set up your own Kubernetes cluster, you can use a tool such as minikube.</description></item><item><title>K3s vs K8s: What are the Differences &amp; Use Cases</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-10-k3s-vs-k8s-what-are-the-differences-use-cases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-10-k3s-vs-k8s-what-are-the-differences-use-cases/</guid><description>What is K8s? Why Use K8s What is K3s? Why Use K3s? When To Use K3s vs Kubernetes Ease of Operations of K8s vs. K3s Disadvantages of K3s Key Differences Wrapping Up Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! But as organizations look to deploy containerized workloads to devices at the edge of their network or for Internet of Things (IoT) applications, the full Kubernetes distribution can be overkill. This is where K3s comes in. Developed by Rancher Labs, K3s is a lightweight Kubernetes distribution designed specifically for resource-constrained edge and IoT environments. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explain the key differences between K3s and the upstream Kubernetes project to help you understand when each makes the most sense for your application architecture and deployment needs. Try the Kubernetes Deployments Lab for free. Kubernetes is an open-source container orchestration platform that automates the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. It allows you to define your application&amp;rsquo;s desired state and ensures that it runs consistently in a cluster of machines. Kubernetes automates tasks such as load balancing, self-healing, and scaling, making it easier to manage and maintain container-based applications. It has become the industry standard for container orchestration, simplifying the management of complex, distributed applications. To learn more about how it works, check out this blog: Kubernetes Architecture Explained: Overview for DevOps Enthusiasts. Scalability and Resource Efficiency - Kubernetes enables easy scaling of your applications up or down based on demand.</description></item><item><title>Should I Use Kubernetes?</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-07-should-i-use-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-06-07-should-i-use-kubernetes/</guid><description>When Should You Use Kubernetes? Microservices architecture Automatic scaling Resource optimization When Should You Avoid Kubernetes? Simple applications Resource constraints Learning curve vs. project timeline Alternative Solutions to Kubernetes Docker Swarm Apache Mesos with Marathon Virtual Machines Conclusion Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! Since its debut in 2014, Kubernetes has seen a meteoric rise in its adoption and popularity. Despite being a relatively new technology, it is now used by a vast number of organizations, from small start-ups to large enterprises, so much so that it has become a standard in the industry. Kubernetes benefits from strong community support and boasts a rich ecosystem of tools and extensions. It is continuously being developed and improved, and judging by the current trends, Kubernetes is only going to get stronger in the future. In this blog post, we’ll discuss why you should consider using Kubernetes , scenarios where Kubernetes might not be the ideal solution, and explore some of its alternatives. Let’s get started! Kubernetes offers several key features that cater to a wide range of application deployment and management needs. Here are the top three features of Kubernetes that make it particularly suitable for modern software development: In recent years, the microservices approach ( where software systems are developed as a collection of small, independent services ) has become increasingly popular in software development. Kubernetes provides many abstractions and APIs that are particularly well-suited to the requirements and characteristics of a microservices architecture. Here&amp;rsquo;s how Kubernetes simplifies the deployment and management of microservices: Containerization support : Kubernetes is designed to manage containers, which are ideal for microservices. Each microservice can be packaged into its own container, encapsulating its dependencies and runtime environment. This makes it easy to deploy and manage microservices consistently and reliably.</description></item><item><title>No More kubectl Commands — Just Talk to Your Kubernetes Cluster in Natural Language</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-28-no-more-kubectl-commands-just-talk-to-your-kubernetes-cluster-in-natural-languag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:52:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-28-no-more-kubectl-commands-just-talk-to-your-kubernetes-cluster-in-natural-languag/</guid><description>Getting Started Install kubectl-ai in Seconds Example 1: Get the Pod Count — Just Ask Example 2: Launch an Nginx Pod in Seconds Example 3: Ask for Nginx Pod Details—No Commands Needed Why This Changes the Game Key Takeaway Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! …and your terminal figured out the rest? &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; how&amp;rsquo;s my nginx app doing? Thanks to kubectl-ai , Kubernetes can now understand natural language. You type what you want in plain English, and it responds by executing real, context-aware kubectl commands — without needing to memorize flags, write YAML, or guess namespaces. kubectl-ai kubectl Let’s explore how this works in action. Before you can chat with your cluster, make sure you have the basics in place: kubectl must be installed and configured for your environment. If you can already run kubectl get pods , you’re good to go. kubectl get pods The fastest way (Linux &amp;amp; macOS): Skip the manual steps and install in one line: curl -sSL https://raw. githubusercontent. com/GoogleCloudPlatform/kubectl-ai/main/install. sh | bash curl -sSL https://raw. githubusercontent. com/GoogleCloudPlatform/kubectl-ai/main/install. sh | bash You’ll be ready to talk to your cluster in under a minute.</description></item><item><title>Do You Need a Degree to Be a DevOps Engineer? A 2025 Guide</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-07-do-you-need-a-degree-to-be-a-devops-engineer-a-2025-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-07-do-you-need-a-degree-to-be-a-devops-engineer-a-2025-guide/</guid><description>The Myth vs. The Reality What Do Employers Really Want? Traditional Degree Pathway The No-Degree Pathway Here’s how you can do the same: Popular Certifications That Replace (or Supplement) a Degree Certs = Proof you know your stuff. The Unspoken DevOps Skills You MUST Have Real Talk: Pros &amp;amp; Cons of Having a Degree Hiring Trends in 2025 and Beyond Pro Tip: Build a DevOps Portfolio Conclusion: Degree or No Degree? DevOps doesn’t care where you came from. It cares what you can deliver. Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! That was the old rulebook. In today’s cloud-powered, open-source-fueled, community-driven tech world… the rules have changed. 👉 The truth? A degree is nice to have, but it’s NOT a mandatory ticket to join the DevOps revolution. 👉 The better question: “Do you have the skills and mindset of a DevOps engineer?” Top companies (even tech giants) now hire for skills, not just degrees. They want someone who can: Solve infrastructure and deployment problems Automate repetitive tasks Improve the development pipeline Collaborate with cross-functional teams In short: They want a problem-solver. A degree shows you can learn. Hands-on skills show you can do. The second matters way more in DevOps.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes 1.33: Top 5 Features of “Octarine</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-05-kubernetes-1-33-top-5-features-of-octarine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-05-kubernetes-1-33-top-5-features-of-octarine/</guid><description>A Closer Look at the Release Stats What You’ll Learn in This Post 1. Sidecar Containers Graduate to Stable The Problem (Before) What’s New in Kubernetes 1.33 Why It Matters 2. In-Place Pod Vertical Scaling (Beta) The Problem (Before) What’s New in Kubernetes 1.33 How to Use It Why It Matters 3. OCI Artifact &amp;amp; Image Volumes (Beta) The Problem (Before) What’s New in Kubernetes 1.33 The Benefits Why It Matters 4. User Namespaces for Pods (Security Beta) The Problem (Before) What’s New in Kubernetes 1.33 How It Works &amp;amp; Usage Why It Matters 5. kubectl. kuberc Configuration (Alpha) The Problem (Before) What’s New in Kubernetes 1.33 How It Works &amp;amp; Usage Why It Matters Wrapping Up: Kubernetes 1.33 Is Ready for You Bonus: Try Kubernetes 1.33 Right Now at KodeKloud Goodbye… Until Next Time! Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! Code-named “Octarine” , a nod to the mythical “color of magic” from Terry Pratchett’s Discworld novels, this release continues Kubernetes’ steady momentum of delivering a scalable, secure, and developer-friendly container orchestration platform. According to the official Kubernetes announcement , Kubernetes 1.33 is all about pushing boundaries while making life easier for everyone working with Kubernetes in production environments. Whether you’re running massive enterprise workloads or experimenting in a dev cluster, this version has something for you. Kubernetes 1.33 includes a total of 64 enhancements , breaking down as follows: 18 Stable (GA) features 20 Beta features 24 Alpha features This broad set of updates signals ongoing investments across the project’s key pillars: performance, scalability, security, extensibility, and usability. With such a packed release, it’s easy to get lost in the full changelog. That’s why we’ve focused this overview on the five most important and popular features that developers and operators are most excited about.</description></item><item><title>Day 7: Your Kubernetes Learning Roadmap — What’s Next After the Basics?</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-03-day-7-your-kubernetes-learning-roadmap-what-s-next-after-the-basics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-03-day-7-your-kubernetes-learning-roadmap-what-s-next-after-the-basics/</guid><description>Congratulations! The Kubernetes Learning Roadmap 1️⃣ Beginner Stage: Solidify the Core 2️⃣ Advanced Beginner Stage: Start Real-World Projects 3️⃣ Intermediate Stage: Kubernetes in Production Bonus: Printable Kubernetes Learning Checklist Final Words of Encouragement Where to Go From Here Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! But Kubernetes is big. It’s normal to now think: This post will give you the answer. Here’s a simple path we recommend: What to learn next: Understand Namespaces ( kubectl get ns ) kubectl get ns Practice creating Pods, Deployments, Services Play with ConfigMaps &amp;amp; Secrets Understand CrashLoopBackOff, Pending Pod errors Tools: 👉 KodeKloud Kubernetes Free Labs 👉 Kubernetes Playground Goal: Be confident to deploy small apps on Kubernetes. What to explore: Volumes &amp;amp; Persistent Storage Kubernetes Networking basics Rolling Updates &amp;amp; Rollbacks Horizontal Pod Autoscaling Tools: 👉 KodeKloud Kubernetes Learning Path Goal: Run small microservices apps in Kubernetes with persistence &amp;amp; scaling. What to master: Ingress Controllers Network Policies Pod Security &amp;amp; RBAC Monitoring with Prometheus + Grafana Troubleshooting broken apps in Kubernetes Helm charts for deploying apps Certification Tip: Start preparing for CKA (Certified Kubernetes Administrator). Tools: 👉 KodeKloud CKA Course 👉 Official Kubernetes Docs Goal: Be job-ready for DevOps &amp;amp; Cloud Native roles. We recommend keeping this simple checklist as your personal tracker : [ ] I understand Containers &amp;amp; Docker [ ] I know how to use kubectl [ ] I can create and manage Pods [ ] I know how Deployments &amp;amp; ReplicaSets work [ ] I can expose apps using Services [ ] I can manage ConfigMaps &amp;amp; Secrets [ ] I understand Clusters, Nodes, and the Control Plane [ ] I ’ve tried Kubernetes labs or playgrounds [ ] I’ve deployed a real-world app in Kubernetes [ ] I ’m exploring intermediate concepts (Volumes, Ingress, Monitoring) [ ] I [ ] I know how to [ ] I [ ] I [ ] I [ ] I [ ] I [ ] I [ ] I’ve deployed a [ ] I 👉 Pro tip: Print it or keep it in Notion/GitHub and check items off as you progress! Kubernetes is NOT something you master overnight. The key is consistent practice + real projects. Even learning these basics puts you ahead of most beginner engineers. 🔎 Keep practicing in the KodeKloud Playground 🎥 Watch Kubernetes beginner &amp;amp; intermediate videos on our KodeKloud YouTube channel 💻 Enroll in guided courses &amp;amp; labs on kodekloud. com You’ve started your Cloud Native journey — keep going. We’ll be here to help every step of the way.</description></item><item><title>Day 6: ConfigMaps &amp; Secrets — Managing App Settings and Sensitive Data in Kubernetes</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-01-day-6-configmaps-secrets-managing-app-settings-and-sensitive-data-in-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 18:11:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-05-01-day-6-configmaps-secrets-managing-app-settings-and-sensitive-data-in-kubernetes/</guid><description>Let’s Begin With What You Might Know What’s a ConfigMap? What’s a Secret? Why Use Them? How It Works Example: Creating a ConfigMap Try It Yourself Real-World Analogy Quick Summary Coming Up. Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! 😬 But in Kubernetes, there’s a better and safer way to do this. Enter: ConfigMaps and Secrets Environment variables App settings File paths Feature flags It keeps your app configs separate from your app code and container image — which is great for flexibility and security. Passwords API tokens TLS certificates Private keys Secrets are base64-encoded and can be managed with tighter access controls in Kubernetes. You: Create a ConfigMap or Secret Attach it to your Pod using: Environment variables Mounted volumes Environment variables Mounted volumes Your app reads the values from the injected location kubectl create configmap app-config \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=APP_ENV=production \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=FEATURE_X=true kubectl create configmap app-config \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=APP_ENV=production \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=FEATURE_X=true And a Secret: kubectl create secret generic db-secret \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=DB_USER=admin \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=DB_PASS=1234 kubectl create secret generic db-secret \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=DB_USER=admin \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=DB_PASS=1234 Then, in your Pod spec (simplified YAML): env: - name: APP_ENV valueFrom: configMapKeyRef: name: app-config key: APP_ENV - name: DB_USER valueFrom: secretKeyRef: name: db-secret key: DB_USER env: - name: APP_ENV valueFrom: configMapKeyRef: name: app-config key: APP_ENV - name: DB_USER valueFrom: secretKeyRef: name: db-secret key: DB_USER 👉 Use the KodeKloud Kubernetes Playground 1 - Create a Secret: kubectl create secret generic mysecret \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=password=mypass123 kubectl create secret generic mysecret \ &amp;ndash;from-literal=password=mypass123 2 - Create a Pod using that secret: apiVersion: v1 kind: Pod metadata: name: secret-demo spec: containers: - name: busybox image: busybox command: [&amp;ldquo;sleep&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;3600&amp;rdquo;] env: - name: DB_PASSWORD valueFrom: secretKeyRef: name: mysecret key: password apiVersion: v1 kind: Pod metadata: name: secret-demo spec: containers: - name: busybox image: busybox command: [&amp;ldquo;sleep&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;3600&amp;rdquo;] env: - name: DB_PASSWORD valueFrom: secretKeyRef: name: mysecret key: password Apply it with: kubectl apply -f pod. yaml kubectl exec -it secret-demo &amp;ndash; printenv DB_PASSWORD kubectl apply -f pod. yaml kubectl exec -it secret-demo &amp;ndash; printenv DB_PASSWORD You’ll see the password securely injected. Imagine you’re deploying an app on a shared team server. Hardcoding passwords in the app = leaving your house key in plain sight Using ConfigMaps and Secrets = storing your keys in a locked drawer with access logs ConfigMaps store general config data (non-sensitive) Secrets store sensitive info (passwords, tokens) Both can be injected into Pods via env vars or mounted files They help decouple config from code , enable reuse, and improve security 📅 Day 7: Your Kubernetes Learning Roadmap — What’s Next After the Basics? You’ll get: A printable roadmap for beginners → advanced Tips on real-world practice Recommended projects, labs, and courses to continue your journey New here? Start from Day 1 and catch up on the series: Day 1: What Is Kubernetes &amp;amp; Why Should You Care? Discover why Kubernetes matters and how it changes the game. Day 2: What Are Pods in Kubernetes? Understand the smallest deployable unit in Kubernetes. Day 3: Understanding Nodes, Clusters &amp;amp; the Kubernetes Control Plane See how all the pieces connect behind the scenes. Day 4: Deployments &amp;amp; ReplicaSets — How Kubernetes Runs and Manages Your App ⚙Learn how Kubernetes keeps your apps running smoothly.</description></item><item><title>Day 5: Kubernetes Services — How Your App Gets a Stable IP or URL</title><link>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-04-29-day-5-kubernetes-services-how-your-app-gets-a-stable-ip-or-url/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubermates.org/docs/2025-04-29-day-5-kubernetes-services-how-your-app-gets-a-stable-ip-or-url/</guid><description>Let’s Start With What You Might Know What Is a Kubernetes Service? How It Works Example Types of Services (Simplified) Real-World Analogy Try It Out Quick Summary Coming Up. Exploring System Architecture for DevOps Engineers Why KubeCon India 2025 Meant More to KodeKloud Linux: List Disks Linux: &amp;ldquo;cat&amp;rdquo; Command Linux Made Easy for DevOps Beginners From CFP to Stage: Win Your Tech Talk Slot MCP Explained Simply: How AI Can Actually Do Things Now Still Not Job-Ready After Learning DevOps? What Is Kubernetes? Finally, a Simple Explanation! But here’s the next problem: You try running: kubectl get pods -o wide kubectl get pods -o wide And you see something like: NAME READY STATUS IP NODE myapp-xyz 1/1 Running 10.244.1.5 worker-node-1 NAME READY STATUS IP NODE myapp-xyz 1/1 Running 10.244.1.5 worker-node-1 Great — but: That Pod IP is internal It changes if the Pod dies and restarts And if you have 3 replicas… which IP do you even hit? That’s where Services come in. You can think of it as: A permanent IP address or DNS name inside the cluster A load balancer that routes traffic to the right Pods A gateway between your app and the outside world (if needed) You attach a Service to a set of Pods using labels The Service tracks the matching Pods — even as Pods come and go Kubernetes uses something called kube-proxy to route traffic to the correct Pod behind the scenes So even if Pods restart, the Service endpoint never changes. Let’s say you run 3 Pods of a web app with the label: app: myapp app: myapp You create a Service like this: selector: app: myapp selector: app: myapp Now, when someone accesses the Service: Kubernetes forwards the request to any of the healthy Pods It’s automatic, balanced, and reliable Imagine your app’s Pods are like food trucks moving around a festival ground. A Service is like the signpost that says: You don’t care where the trucks are parked — you just follow the sign. Kubernetes routes you to the right place, even if trucks come and go. Use the Kubernetes Playground: 👉 KodeKloud Kubernetes Playground Create a deployment: kubectl create deployment myapp &amp;ndash;image=nginx kubectl expose deployment myapp &amp;ndash;port=80 &amp;ndash;type=NodePort kubectl get service kubectl create deployment myapp &amp;ndash;image=nginx kubectl expose deployment myapp &amp;ndash;port=80 &amp;ndash;type=NodePort kubectl get service Now run: kubectl get pods -o wide kubectl describe service myapp kubectl get pods -o wide kubectl describe service myapp Look for the NodePort (e. g. , 30123 ) and try opening: 30123 http://&lt;worker-node-ip&gt;:30123 http://&lt;worker-node-ip&gt;:30123 You’re now accessing your app through a Kubernetes Service! Pods have dynamic IPs and can restart anytime A Service gives your app a stable endpoint Services load-balance traffic to healthy Pods You can expose your app internally or externally with different service types 📅 Day 6: ConfigMaps &amp;amp; Secrets — Managing App Settings and Sensitive Data You’ll learn: Why you should never hardcode passwords or configs in containers How Kubernetes separates config data and secrets How to use them in real applications New here? Start from Day 1 and catch up on the series: Day 1: What Is Kubernetes &amp;amp; Why Should You Care? Discover why Kubernetes matters and how it changes the game. Day 2: What Are Pods in Kubernetes? Understand the smallest deployable unit in Kubernetes. Day 3: Understanding Nodes, Clusters &amp;amp; the Kubernetes Control Plane See how all the pieces connect behind the scenes. Day 4: Deployments &amp;amp; ReplicaSets — How Kubernetes Runs and Manages Your App Learn how Kubernetes keeps your apps running smoothly.</description></item></channel></rss>